<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content"><channel><title>Keith Moon's Personal Blog</title><description>No. Not that one.</description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 14:58:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 14:58:41 +0000</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://www.keefmoon.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2017-03-22-just-open-source</guid><title>Just Open Source</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2017-03-22-just-open-source</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="../../images/JustOpenSource.jpg" alt="Just Open Source"/><p>One of the advantages of working with Just Eat is their commitment to Open Source. As an iOS team at Just Eat we are always looking for ways to separate our code into useful, self contained components, and where possible, make them available to the community.</p><p>Recently I've been involved in open sourcing 2 Swift modules, with 1 more that can hopefully be open sourced soon.</p><h2>Just Persist</h2><p>The ability to persist data is a key component for many apps, and all too often as your app grows in complexity, you find the implementation details of your persistence solution littered throughout your codebase.</p><p>This is not ideal. No matter which persistence solution you choose, Core Data, Realm, User Defaults, Keychain, to name a few, your requirements may change as your app grows. When you do need to change your persistence solution, unpicking all the related code is no small task. Testing can also be tricky, with complex persistence stacks needing to be setup and torn down.</p><p>JustPersist aims to provide a implementation agnostic interface to your persistence solution. By keeping your persistence layer behind the JustPersist interface, you ensure testability and the ability to swap out persistence solutions as your needs change.</p><p>Here this the <a href="https://tech.just-eat.com/2017/03/02/how-to-abstract-your-persistence-layer-and-migrate-to-another-one-on-ios-with-justpersist">Just Eat tech blog post</a>.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/justeat/JustPersist">JustPersist can be found on GitHub</a></p><h2>Just Promises</h2><p>A key non functional requirement if any app is that it is quick, smooth and responsive. To achieve this, you will be frequently working with asynchronous code. Grand Central Dispatch is great, but jumping back and forth between queues can easily become unwieldy with nested blocks.</p><p>JustPromises is a framework for doing asynchronous work, based on the "promise" concept, popular in JavaScript. JustPromises is used used heavily in the Just Eat app, and was written in Objective-C a few years ago. As we move more and more of the Just Eat app to Swift 3, the Objective-C interface of JustPromises was really showing it's age. So I undertook to rewrite it in Swift 3.</p><p>Doing a full rewrite enabled me to take full advantage of Swift's generics system and other advanced Swift features. It also allowed me to tidy up the conceptual model and base the <code></code><code>Promise</code><code></code> on <code></code><code>Operation</code><code></code> (formally <code></code><code>NSOperation</code><code></code>), since handling a long running task is exactly what <code></code><code>Operation</code><code></code>s are built for.</p><p>Here is the <a href="https://twitter.com/justeat_tech">@justeat_tech</a> @justeat_tech twitter account, announcing the release:</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The iOS team is proud to release a major update of JustPromises rewritten in Swift 3 😎 <a href="https://t.co/cSr4tpyfIR">https://t.co/cSr4tpyfIR</a></p>&mdash; JUST EAT Technology (@justeat_tech) <a href="https://twitter.com/justeat_tech/status/805746214356611076">December 5, 2016</a></blockquote><script async src="https://www.keefmoon.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script><p>JustPromises is available in Objective-C, Swift or both, from <a href="https://github.com/justeat/JustPromises">GitHub</a> or <a href="https://cocoapods.org/?q=JustPromises">Cocoapods</a></p><h2>Other iOS Open Source</h2><p>The rest of the Just Eat iOS team have also been busy contributing to the open source community</p><h3>Just Track</h3><p>JustTrack is an event tracker.</p><ul><li>Events are declared in a .plist file and Swift 3 code is automatically generated at build time from it.</li><li>Events can be sent to multiple destinations (called Trackers) at the same time.</li><li>Custom Trackers are easy to create and use.</li></ul><p><a href="https://tech.just-eat.com/2017/02/01/ios-event-tracking-with-justtrack/">JustTrack Blog Post</a> - <a href="https://github.com/justeat/JustTrack">JustTrack GitHub Page</a></p><h3>Just Log</h3><p>Remote logging to multiple providers from one interface.</p><p><a href="https://tech.just-eat.com/2017/01/18/a-better-local-and-remote-logging-on-ios-with-justlog/">JustLog Blog Post</a> - <a href="https://github.com/justeat/JustLog">JustLog GitHub Page</a></p><h3>Just Peek</h3><p>JustPeek ports Force-Touch Peek/Pop-like interactions to devices that aren’t force-touch enabled.</p><p><a href="https://tech.just-eat.com/2016/12/01/introducing-justpeek/">JustPeek Blog Post</a> - <a href="https://github.com/justeat/JustPeek">JustPeek GitHub Page</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2017-02-15-catch-up</guid><title>It's been a while...</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2017-02-15-catch-up</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 23:20:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>It's been a while...</h1><p>It's been a long time since I posted on this blog, and every time I consider a post I want to write, I think about all the things I could/should have blogged about since my last post. But jumping to an up to date topic, I feel like I closed the book on the other things I should already have mentioned.</p><p>So, to free me up to blog about anything I feel like, here is a rapid fire round up of blog-worthy things, since my last post:</p><ul><li>I spent a long time working with a great team on a version 3.0 of the <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/bbc-news/id377382255?mt=8">BBC News app on iOS</a>, it was going to be GREAT... and then it all fell apart. We lost support from management, and the team imploded. Maybe someday I'll post the follow story of what happened. I've no idea how much of my code ended up in the app that was released, but I'm still proud of the work we did.</li></ul><ul><li>I worked on the app for <a href="http://supercard.io">Supercard by Travelex</a>, cool product, and it was a nice app, had some cool little flourishes. I lead a small team, and we built it in about 3 months.</li></ul><ul><li>Next, I joined a team at <a href="http://www.aimia.com">Aimia</a>, the company behind the <a href="http://www.nectar.com">Nectar loyalty scheme</a>. The company was undergoing an "agile transformation", and our team worked with a fantastic agile coach, who helped us setup a great Kanban system that made us really efficient.</li></ul><ul><li>In the summer of 2015, I worked on a complete redesign of the <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/nct-babychange/id427067798?mt=8">Babychange app</a> I built for the <a href="https://www.nct.org.uk">NCT</a> (did I mention that it is <a href="../nct-babychange-award-winning">award winning</a>? ;)). I decided to undertake the ground up rewrite in the newly available <a href="https://swift.org">Swift programming language</a>. Building an app end to end in Swift was a fantastic learning experience, and was very useful for what came next...</li></ul><ul><li>In October 2015 I joined a newly formed team to build a <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/travelsupermarket-cheap-holidays/id1076336923?mt=8">flagship app</a> for <a href="https://www.travelsupermarket.com">Travel Supermarket</a>. We had a great team, comprising some of the best developers I've worked with, and we decided to jump into Swift development with both feet. We built a very modular architecture, using Swift access control to enforce good separation of concerns. Turns out other people thought this was a good idea too, and called it <a href="https://christiantietze.de/posts/2017/01/oop-framework-oriented-programming">Framework Orientated Programming</a>.</li></ul><ul><li>Since July 2016, I've been working with <a href="https://www.just-eat.co.uk">Just Eat</a> as part of the payment team. It's a great place to work.</li></ul><ul><li>In November 2016, I spoke at the <a href="http://mbltdev.ru/en">MBLT.dev</a> conference in Moscow, with a talk called "Thinking in Swift". It seemed to be well received. The video of the <a href="https://youtu.be/MNrvQ5tt8dU?list=PLufI-p7bsMuTsKqt5O51J5OsAm-sH9osH">talk is available on YouTube</a>, and the <a href="https://github.com/keefmoon/ThinkingInSwift">code and slides are available on GitHub</a>.</li></ul><p>So, with all that off my chest, now I can write about what ever comes up.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2013-04-07-bbc-news-for-ios-20</guid><title>BBC News for iOS 2.0</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2013-04-07-bbc-news-for-ios-20</link><pubDate>Sun, 7 Apr 2013 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>BBC News for iOS 2.0</h1><p>For just over the last 4 months, I’ve been leading a small team that has been working to update the BBC News App for iPhone and iPad.</p><p>This new version went live this week and is a significant update. The App has been re-built from the ground up, allowing for a refreshed UI, and addresses a number of bugs and stability issues with the previous version.</p><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_inline_mkwg7aj6qN1qz4rgp.png" alt="BBC News iPad app screenshot"/><p>The update also improved the accessibility of the App, ensuring VoiceOver users can navigate the App with ease.</p><p>Response to version 2.0 has been overwhelmingly positive:</p><blockquote><p>Rupert Maspero (<a href="http://twitter.com/rmaspero">@rmaspero</a>) BBC’s update to their news app is a huge improvement!<a href="https://twitter.com/rmaspero/status/319043775282421760">https://twitter.com/rmaspero/status/319043775282421760</a></p></blockquote><blockquote><p>Lance Andrewes (<a href="http://twitter.com/lanceanz">@lanceanz</a>) Today’s update of BBC News for iOS is a major one. Layout has been revamped, and it’s clearly faster.<a href="https://twitter.com/lanceanz/status/316972126756286464">https://twitter.com/lanceanz/status/316972126756286464</a></p></blockquote><p>And the iPad App was picked an Editor’s Choice by the App Store:</p><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_inline_mkwfmjIkB81qz4rgp.png" alt="BBC News app featured in the App Store"/><p>We have noticed a few niggling issues, that will hope to address with an update soon, but in all a very successful launch, and an App we are proud of.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2013-03-20-sponsor-me-to-run-the-london-marathon-almost</guid><title>Sponsor me to run the London marathon (almost) barefoot</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2013-03-20-sponsor-me-to-run-the-london-marathon-almost</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 08:40:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Sponsor me to run the London marathon (almost) barefoot</h1><p>I will be running in this year’s London Marathon, and to be honest, I’ve left the fundraising quite late.</p><p>I am running to raise money for the NSPCC, which is a fantastic charity that does great work.</p><p>This is my first marathon, although I’ve run 2 half marathon’s previously. As if that wasn’t enough of a challenge, I’ll be running it barefoot…. sort of.</p><p>Instead of running in cushioned trainers, I will be running the marathon in minimalist footwear that does little more than stop my feet getting cut on sharp stones.</p><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_inline_mjxm1tIQGd1qz4rgp.jpg" alt="Vibram Five Fingers"/><p>You can find out more about barefoot and minimalist running on Wikipedia: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barefoot_running">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barefoot_running</a></p><p>I am looking to reach a sponsorship goal of £2,000 so please sponsor me anything you can spare.</p><p>To sponsor me, please visit <a href="http://keef.me/barefoot-sponsor">http://keef.me/barefoot-sponsor</a> or you can text <code>KEEF55</code> and an amount to 70070. For example, sending the following text:</p><p><code>KEEF55 £10</code> to 70070 would sponsor me for £10 and be much appreciated.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2013-01-14-great-ios-bluetooth-tutorial</guid><title>Great iOS Bluetooth Tutorial</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2013-01-14-great-ios-bluetooth-tutorial</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 23:59:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Great iOS Bluetooth Tutorial</h1><p><a href="http://invasivecode.tumblr.com/post/39707371281/core-bluetooth-for-ios-core-bluetooth-was">Great iOS Bluetooth Tutorial</a></p><p>Looking forward to trying out some Bluetooth goodness.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-11-18-so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish</guid><title>So long, and thanks for all the fish.</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-11-18-so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 23:27:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>So long, and thanks for all the fish.</h1><img src="{{ site.url }}/tumblr_files/hotels-com-banner.jpg" alt="Hotels.com banner"/><p>Friday was my last day at <a href="http://www.hotels.com">Hotels.com</a>, I’m leaving for a new contract at the BBC.</p><p>I have been working there for nearly a year and have enjoyed my time immensely. I have made some really good friends and greatly improved my understanding of software development practices, and I put that down to the great working environment and the skill and patience of my colleagues.</p><p>My team bought me the most amazing leaving present ever, THE BIGGEST MUG IN THE WORLD, which they all signed. Thanks all :)</p><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/8197190561_cbff33918f_k.jpg" alt="Keith with the biggest mug in the world"/>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-11-13-it-project-team-of-the-year-finalist</guid><title>IT Project Team of the Year Finalist</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-11-13-it-project-team-of-the-year-finalist</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>IT Project Team of the Year Finalist</h1><p>The Hotels.com iOS team has been <a href="http://www.bcs.org/content/ConWebDoc/47713">named as a finalist</a> for the BCS IT Industry Awards 2012, in the category IT Project Team of the Year.</p><p>I <a href="../2012-09-27-shortlisted-for-a-uk-it-industry-award">wrote about being shortlisted</a>, but we have made it to the final, and representatives will be attending a black tie awards ceremony tomorrow (Wed 14th Nov).</p><p>Fingers crossed!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-09-27-shortlisted-for-a-uk-it-industry-award</guid><title>Shortlisted for a UK IT Industry Award</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-09-27-shortlisted-for-a-uk-it-industry-award</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Shortlisted for a UK IT Industry Award</h1><p>The Hotels.com iOS team (which I am currently a part of) has been shortlisted for a UK IT Industry Award in the category of IT Project Team of the Year.</p><p><a href="http://www.ukitindustryawards.co.uk/static/2012-shortlist">UK IT Industry Awards Shortlist</a></p><p>I’m told the award is specifically for the iPad App project, which we as a team have been improving over the last year. You can download <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hotels.com-hd/id461327349?mt=8">Hotels.com HD for your iPad from the App Store</a></p><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/hotels-com-ipad.png" alt="Hotels.com iPad app screenshot"/>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-06-07-i-was-asked-to-provide-an-simple-explanation-of</guid><title>Anatomy of a Request</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-06-07-i-was-asked-to-provide-an-simple-explanation-of</link><pubDate>Thu, 7 Jun 2012 10:06:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Anatomy of a Request</h1><p>I was asked to provide an simple explanation of how an iPhone App interacts with, and retrieves data from, a web service, such as we use at Hotels.com. It seems to have been really helpful for some non-technical people here, and so I thought is might be helpful for others. Created on my journey home one day, using <a href="http://t.umblr.com/redirect?z=http%3A%2F%2Fitunes.apple.com%2Fgb%2Fapp%2Fomnigraffle%2Fid363225984%3Fmt%3D8&t=Y2Q5NWEzOWMxY2I2NTFiODFkYTVlNTgyNDIyNzE4OWRjMTFlNDM4Mix5SXcySHp4WQ%3D%3D&b=t%3AFWXc4HC6zAL6f3DZ4FKykw&m=1">OmniGraffle for iPad</a>.</p><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_m58pauizt01r4drs9o1_1280.png" alt="Anatomy of a request diagram"/>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-05-15-shakespeares-london-the-app-i-built-with-victor</guid><title>Shakespeare's London in Time Out</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-05-15-shakespeares-london-the-app-i-built-with-victor</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 21:18:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Shakespeare's London in Time Out</h1><p>Shakespeare's London, the App I built with <a href="http://twitter.com/vickeegan">Victor Keegan</a> was featured in this week’s Time Out.</p><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_m42z31mv381r4drs9o1_1280.png" alt="Shakespeare's London in TimeOut"/>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-05-15-lightbox-blog-lightbox-is-joining-facebook</guid><title>'Lightbox Blog: Lightbox is joining Facebook!'</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-05-15-lightbox-blog-lightbox-is-joining-facebook</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>'Lightbox Blog: Lightbox is joining Facebook!'</h1><p>I used to sit next to these guys. Congratulations Lightbox!</p><p><a href="http://blog.lightbox.com/post/23107101360/lightbox-is-joining-facebook">lightboxapp</a>:</p><blockquote><p>We started Lightbox because we were excited about creating new services built primarily for mobile, especially for the Android and HTML5 platforms, and we’re honored that millions of you have downloaded the Lightbox Photos app and shared your experiences with the Lightbox community.Today,…</p></blockquote>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-05-15-victor-keegan-demoing-our-iphone-app-gems-of</guid><title>Demoing Gems of London</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-05-15-victor-keegan-demoing-our-iphone-app-gems-of</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 19:32:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Demoing Gems of London</h1><p><a href="http://twitter.com/vickeegan">Victor Keegan</a> demoing our iPhone App Gems of London</p><iframe width="400" height="300"  id="youtube_iframe" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HdhzwDdNWps?feature=oembed&enablejsapi=1&origin=http://safe.txmblr.com&wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-05-04-entertaining-recruitment-video-from-expedia</guid><title>Entertaining Recruitment Video from Expedia</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-05-04-entertaining-recruitment-video-from-expedia</link><pubDate>Fri, 4 May 2012 13:12:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Entertaining Recruitment Video from Expedia</h1><p>Entertaining recruitment video from Expedia, featuring the building I currently work in for Expedia/Hotels.com</p><iframe width="400" height="225"  id="youtube_iframe" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4ZGOHRrXfJk?feature=oembed&enablejsapi=1&origin=http://safe.txmblr.com&wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-04-17-nct-babychange-listed-in-the-top-10-parenting-apps</guid><title>NCT Babychange listed in the Top 10 Parenting Apps</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-04-17-nct-babychange-listed-in-the-top-10-parenting-apps</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 12:38:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>NCT Babychange listed in the Top 10 Parenting Apps</h1><p>NCT Babychange listed in the Top 10 Parenting AppsI’m a bit late in posting this as it happened a couple of weeks ago, but my App for the NCT has been listed by The Independent as one of the Top 10 App for parents.</p><p>Details here <a href="http://keef.me/Top10Parenting">http://keef.me/Top10Parenting</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-02-24-audiofuel-in-the-top-50-innovative-uk-apps</guid><title>AudioFuel in the Top 50 Innovative UK Apps</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-02-24-audiofuel-in-the-top-50-innovative-uk-apps</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>AudioFuel in the Top 50 Innovative UK Apps</h1><p>My AudioFuel App has been listed as in The App Side’s list of 50 Innovative App from the UK. The report is embedded below.</p><p><a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/82564623">Apps Report</a></p><iframe class="scribd_iframe_embed" frameborder="0" height="600" id="doc_92882" scrolling="no" src="http://www.scribd.com/embeds/82564623/content?start_page=1&amp;view_mode=list" width="100%"></iframe>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-02-17-my-new-app-hidden-gems-of-london-built-in</guid><title>Hidden Gems of London</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-02-17-my-new-app-hidden-gems-of-london-built-in</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 21:32:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Hidden Gems of London</h1><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_lzk3tlymj71r4drs9o1_1280.png" alt="Gems of London screenshot"/><p>My new App, Hidden Gems of London, built in collaboration with Victor Keegan, is now live in the App Store!</p><p><a href="http://keef.me/LDNGems">http://keef.me/LDNGems</a></p><p>Our App shows you a London that isn’t in the guide books, highlighting hidden places and features.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-02-09-the-award-winning-nct-babychanging-app-that-i</guid><title>NCT Babychange in 500 Best Apps</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-02-09-the-award-winning-nct-babychanging-app-that-i</link><pubDate>Thu, 9 Feb 2012 14:47:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>NCT Babychange in 500 Best Apps</h1><p>The award-winning NCT Babychanging App that I built for the National Childbirth Trust has now had a new honour bestowed upon it. Two weekends ago it was selected for the Sunday Times App List, which selects and categories the 500 best Apps in the App Store. I didn’t get a copy of the print version, so here is a screenshot from the Sunday Times iPad App.</p><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_lz4rqktkVx1r4drs9o1_1280.png" alt="The Sunday Times app screenshot"/>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-02-06-what-i-have-to-do-to-get-siri-to-tell-me-the</guid><title>What I have to do to get Siri to tell me the time</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-02-06-what-i-have-to-do-to-get-siri-to-tell-me-the</link><pubDate>Mon, 6 Feb 2012 22:45:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>What I have to do to get Siri to tell me the time</h1><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-1v6BnkT4X0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>Siri is awesome and I use it all the time, but sometime it seems to over complicate things.</p><p>Before Siri there was Voice Control, it did simple things like playing music, voice dialing and tell you the time. However in some instances, Siri seems like a step backwards.</p><p>For something as simple as asking for the time, instead of just repeating the iPhone’s current time, it now requires an Internet connection and uses your location to determine your time zone…. except that it doesn’t seem to be able to tie your, very accurate, location to a particular time zone.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-01-25-high-schools-are-step-one-of-two</guid><title>High Schools Are Step One Of Two</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-01-25-high-schools-are-step-one-of-two</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 21:52:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>High Schools Are Step One Of Two</h1><p>High Schools Are Step One Of TwoNot sure how I feel about Apple owning the whole education market, which is clearly what they are trying to do. But change is needed and if this is how it happens then so be it.</p><p><a href="http://blog.mckaythomas.com/post/16294083795/high-schools-are-step-one-of-two">mckaythomas</a>:</p><blockquote><p>MG Siegler in his latest TechCrunch article posits that although Apple’s new iBooks strategy is admirable in its effort to fix problems in public high schools, that it’s not realistic and that their market strategy should revolve around colleges and college textbooks.On the surface, which seems logical enough, his argument is sound. But It ignores the one, HUGE driving force in education: money.Nearly all high schools are public, or receive public funding in one way or another and help to satisfy the law which states that students of high school age must attend school. Textbooks are merely a means of teaching these students topics which help these schools qualify for their funding. That’s basically the business model for most high schools in the US. Teach what the state and federal governments mandate to receive funding.Universities do not work that way. Even so called “public universities”. These are institutions that operate on revenues, which come from donations, returns from investments, tuition, and from selling products. That last item is particularly important when applied to the university bookstores.Bookstores are profit centers for universities. Big ones. As tablets (by tablets, I really mean iPads) have come out over the last few years startups have emerged to help university students get their hands on digital textbooks. And it’s exciting. We can look at the the progress they are making and feel like the education world is progressing. But it isn’t. Kno, one of the most prominent digital textbook sellers, still only offers a very small percentage of textbooks required for university classes. And many textbooks still require the purchase of a physical book to qualify for the digital version. This is because students are currently not the customers of textbook publishers. University bookstores are. And by removing the university bookstore middle man, you evaporate millions of dollars in revenue for each university. And they know this. And are fighting hard for the publishers to maintain the current model.Here’s where Apple’s brilliant strategy comes in. They know the power of amazing devices in markets. They know the strength of the consumer’s collective voice. They watched as the nation coalesced behind their $.99 solution for music, which ended up cutting the size of the music industry in half. The new iBook textbooks are being marketed in a way that circumvents the university bookstore. Brilliant. Go right to the student in high school. Make them a true believer. Give them an amazing textbook experience starting in 9th grade. By the time these students hit university in 4 more years they aren’t going to know how to not use an iPad while studying. The iPad will be synonymous with learning, and that’s when education shifts. If textbook publishers continue to exclude students from their market strategy students will take matters in their own hands. Things will get crazy. And that’s when industries get disrupted. When the end user is fed up and frustrated and motivated to make a difference. And college students have always been the most adept protestors and rioters.Apple, by going high school first, is applying the heat to university textbook publishers and bookstores. They are saying “Fine. If you won’t work with us, then we’ll empower a generation to change your industry for you.”And they will.To MG’s point, the high school strategy is still tricky. We are dealing with young teenagers here and PUBLIC schools, which means there isn’t a lot of cash to go around. But they’ll figure it out. The iPad is only on its second generation and my mom, a 9th grade history teacher, already has one, curtesy of her school. Students are next. Then on to the revolution.</p></blockquote>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-01-16-free-scrum-ebook</guid><title>Free Scrum eBook</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-01-16-free-scrum-ebook</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 21:28:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Free Scrum eBook</h1><p>I’ve been wanting to learn about the Scrum framework for software development for a while, and I now find myself knee-deep in it with my current iOS contract. It’s a lot less scary than it seemed and here is a free eBook with practical implementation examples:</p><p><a href="http://www.infoq.com/minibooks/scrum-xp-from-the-trenches">http://www.infoq.com/minibooks/scrum-xp-from-the-trenches</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-01-16-a-rainbow-at-its-peak</guid><title>A Rainbow At Its Peak</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2012-01-16-a-rainbow-at-its-peak</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 16:35:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>A Rainbow At Its Peak</h1><p>Nice graph. Will be interesting to see the update in 5 or 10 years.</p><p><a href="http://parislemon.com/post/15950097492/a-rainbow-at-its-peak">parislemon</a>:</p><p>&gt;Horace Dediu presents yet another amazing way to look at the rapidly evolving computer industry (here are Dediu’s other fascinating looks of the past few days). The PC looks like a rainbow at its peak. The Macintosh looks like a roller coaster with a misleading small first hill that tricks riders. Android, iPhone, and iPad look like fireworks just taking off… &gt; <img src="http://65.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lxwfx3cwMz1qz4gev.png" alt="Graph of units shipped per year"/></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-25-nct-babychange-award-winning</guid><title>NCT Babychange - Award Winning!</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-25-nct-babychange-award-winning</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 15:21:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>NCT Babychange - Award Winning!</h1><p>My App for the NCT, NCT Babychange, won an award on Wednesday! Best Mobile Solution at the APA International Content Marketing Awards.</p><p>Details here <a href="http://keef.me/NCTAPAAward ">http://keef.me/NCTAPAAward</a></p><p>App here <a href="http://keef.me/nctapp">http://keef.me/nctapp</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-25-today-is-my-last-day-at-mobile-roadie-my-time</guid><title>Last day at Mobile Roadie</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-25-today-is-my-last-day-at-mobile-roadie-my-time</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 13:19:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Last day at Mobile Roadie</h1><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_lv7x0dvcU71r4drs9o1_1280.jpg" alt="Mobile Roadie banner"/><p>Today is my last day at Mobile Roadie.</p><p>My time with Mobile Roadie has been amazing, we’ve won awards, we’ve <a href="../2011-10-24-its-not-often-you-get-to-say-that-your-job-took">been to Downing Street</a>, and we’ve <a href="../2011-10-21-beanbags-have-arrived-at-the-mobile-roadie-office">built up the UK office</a> into a really cool place to work.</p><p>But it’s time for me to move on. I’m leaving the warm comfy embrace of permanent employment and into the harsh cold reality of freelance work. I’ve got a initial contract to get me going, which is very exciting, and I’ll post more about it when I’m up and running.</p><p>Thank you to everyone at <a href="https://mobileroadie.com/">Mobile Roadie</a> for teaching me so much over the past year, and allowing me to be part of an amazing team. Special thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/steoreilly">Stephen O'Reilly</a> and Ash Lim for making Mobile Roadie UK as awesome, fun and friendly as it is, and to Steve Schroeder for being one of the smartest guys I know and teaching me so much.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-24-sparrowios</guid><title>Sparrow on iOS</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-24-sparrowios</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2011 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Sparrow on iOS</h1><blockquote><p><img src="http://65.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lu393nRMhV1qbptnpo1_500.jpg" alt="iPhone on table showing SparrowMail"/></p></blockquote><p>I LOVE Sparrow mail App on OSX, and the idea of it on the iPhone is very exciting. I’ve never liked the default Mail App, and wondered why no-one was making mail clients on iOS. I assumed the Apple would claim that it duplicated built-in functionality, maybe they changed the policy recently, since the GMail App is now out. sparrowmail:</p><p>&gt;As seen on The Verge and Business Insider, here is a preview of Sparrow for iPhone.</p><p>(Source: <a href="http://sparrowmail.tumblr.com/post/12283842323/sparrowios">sparrowmail</a>)</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-22-facebook-not-building-a-phone</guid><title>Facebook Not Building A Phone</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-22-facebook-not-building-a-phone</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 12:42:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Facebook Not Building A Phone</h1><p>&gt;No Facebook employee is actually on an assembly line building phone hardware. There are two things I like about the AllThingsD (or as John Gruber likes to call them “some website”) report on the “Facebook Phone”. 1) The complete and utter lack of any link to or mention of TechCrunch even though we broke this story over a year ago. Do they have new information? Yes, namely the codename, “Buffy”, and the partnership with HTC. But it is the same project, as they even acknowledge: “Although it has changed scope and leadership, Buffy has been an ongoing area of concern at the social networking giant for the past two years.” 2) While Facebook denied the project at the time of our report, there’s no question it has been real the entire time. I’m going to stick by what I wrote last September: Facebook Is Not Working On A Phone Just Like Google Was Not Working On A Phone. In that post, I outlined exactly what these new reports suggest. Namely that Facebook has been working on their own version of Android with social deeply ingrained — which Dan Frommer was first to point out on Business Insider also over a year ago, and I reiterated hearing this past February. And working with a third-party to manufacturer the hardware (again, HTC).</p><p>(Source: <a href="http://parislemon.com/post/13133436583/facebook-not-building-a-phone">parislemon</a>)</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-05-siri-does-this-to-me-too-very-annoying-although</guid><title>Siri Time</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-05-siri-does-this-to-me-too-very-annoying-although</link><pubDate>Sat, 5 Nov 2011 19:33:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Siri Time</h1><p>Siri does this to me too. Very annoying. Although, if I say “What time is it in London?” I get the answer.</p><blockquote><p><img src="http://66.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lu44tsZxdC1r4eoiuo1_1280.png" alt="Siri conversation about time"/></p></blockquote><p>(Source: <a href="http://shitthatsirisays.tumblr.com/post/12377100993">shitthatsirisays</a>)</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-05-im-5-days-into-movember-please-sponsor-me-at</guid><title>5 days into Movember</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-05-im-5-days-into-movember-please-sponsor-me-at</link><pubDate>Sat, 5 Nov 2011 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>5 days into Movember</h1><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_lu78tsMv361r4drs9o1_1280.png" alt="5 days into Movember"/><p>I’m 5 days into Movember. Please sponsor me at <a href="http://mobro.co/keefmoon">http://mobro.co/keefmoon</a> and see all the pics at <a href="http://keef.me/fbmopics">http://keef.me/fbmopics</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-04-yield-thought-i-swapped-my-macbook-for-an</guid><title>'Yield Thought: I swapped my MacBook for an iPad+Linode'</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-11-04-yield-thought-i-swapped-my-macbook-for-an</link><pubDate>Fri, 4 Nov 2011 12:43:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>'Yield Thought: I swapped my MacBook for an iPad+Linode'</h1><p><a href="http://yieldthought.com/post/12239282034/swapped-my-macbook-for-an-ipad">Yield Thought: I swapped my MacBook for an iPad+Linode</a></p><blockquote><p>On September 19th, I said goodbye to my trusty MacBook Pro and started developing exclusively on an iPad + Linode 512. This is the surprising story of a month spent working in the cloud.It all started when I bought my first MacBook a couple of years ago. Frustrated by the inconsistent…</p></blockquote>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-10-24-its-not-often-you-get-to-say-that-your-job-took</guid><title>No. 10 Downing Street</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-10-24-its-not-often-you-get-to-say-that-your-job-took</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>No. 10 Downing Street</h1><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/tumblr_ltl9h9kOEo1r4drs9o1_1280.jpg" alt="Keith and Stephen at No. 10"/><p>It’s not often you get to say that your job took you to No. 10 Downing Street :) Stephen and I chatted to the the Prime Minister’s digital team about Apps.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-10-21-beanbags-have-arrived-at-the-mobile-roadie-office</guid><title>Beanbags have arrived at the Mobile Roadie office</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-10-21-beanbags-have-arrived-at-the-mobile-roadie-office</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Beanbags have arrived at the Mobile Roadie office</h1><img src="../../images/tumblr_files/beanbag.jpg" alt="Keith sitting on a beanbag"/><p>Beanbags have arrived at the Mobile Roadie office :)</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-10-12-my-iphone-4s-should-be-here-on-friday-and-i-cant</guid><title>Real World Demo of Siri Personal Assistant on an Apple iPhone 4S</title><description></description><link>https://www.keefmoon.com/posts/2011-10-12-my-iphone-4s-should-be-here-on-friday-and-i-cant</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Real World Demo of Siri Personal Assistant on an Apple iPhone 4S</h1><p>My iPhone 4S should be here on Friday and I can’t wait :)</p><blockquote><p>Real World Demo of Siri Personal Assistant on an Apple iPhone 4S <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MKRwV3DTVLo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p></blockquote><p>(Source: <a href="http://laughingsquid.com/demo-of-siri-on-apple-iphone-4s/">Laughing Squid</a>)</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>